<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.aeroftp.AeroFTP</id>

  <name>AeroFTP</name>
  <summary>Modern Multi-Protocol File Client with AI, Encryption and Cloud Storage</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      AeroFTP is a cross-platform desktop client for FTP, FTPS, SFTP, WebDAV,
      S3-compatible storage, and cloud providers including Google Drive, Dropbox,
      OneDrive, MEGA, Box, pCloud, Azure Blob Storage, 4shared, Filen, Zoho WorkDrive,
      Internxt Drive, kDrive, Koofr, FileLu, Yandex Disk, and OpenDrive. 25 protocols, 30+ presets, one app.
    </p>
    <p>Security and Encryption:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>AeroVault v2: Military-grade encrypted containers with AES-256-GCM-SIV, Argon2id, HMAC-SHA512, and optional ChaCha20 cascade</li>
      <li>Cryptomator format 8 vault support (scrypt + AES-SIV + AES-GCM)</li>
      <li>Universal Credential Vault with AES-256-GCM encryption and optional master password</li>
      <li>Archive encryption: ZIP and 7z with AES-256 password protection</li>
      <li>Memory zeroization for all passwords and keys (Rust secrecy + zeroize)</li>
    </ul>
    <p>AI Assistant:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>AeroAgent Pro: AI-powered assistant with 47 tools, shell command execution, server exec, RAG indexing, plugin system, streaming markdown, prompt templates, and cost budget tracking</li>
      <li>19 AI providers: OpenAI, Anthropic, Google Gemini, xAI Grok, OpenRouter, Ollama, Kimi, Qwen, DeepSeek, Mistral, Groq, Perplexity, Cohere, Together AI, AI21 Labs, Cerebras, SambaNova, Fireworks AI, Custom</li>
      <li>Vision/multimodal: Attach images for analysis with GPT-4o, Claude, Gemini</li>
      <li>Native function calling with streaming responses and cost tracking</li>
    </ul>
    <p>File Management:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Dual-pane file browser with list/grid views, thumbnails, and media player</li>
      <li>Archive browser for ZIP, 7z, TAR, and RAR with selective extraction</li>
      <li>Smart Sync with intelligent conflict resolution (3 modes)</li>
      <li>Batch Rename with 4 modes and live preview</li>
      <li>Monaco code editor (VS Code engine) with syntax highlighting</li>
      <li>Integrated terminal with SSH remote shell and 8 themes</li>
      <li>47 languages at 100% coverage — quality-audited translations with native script integrity</li>
      <li>AeroPlayer: Built-in media player with 14 visualizer modes, WebGL GPU shaders, 10-band EQ, and beat detection</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Command-Line Interface:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>AeroFTP CLI: 14 commands across 12 protocols with JSON output, glob transfers, and batch scripting</li>
      <li>Batch engine: .aeroftp script files with variables, error policies, and 16 commands</li>
      <li>Security hardened: path traversal prevention, ANSI sanitization, OOM protection, 45-finding audit</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Built with Rust (Tauri 2) and React 18/TypeScript. Open source under GPL-3.0.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">AeroFTP.desktop</launchable>

  <mimetypes>
    <mimetype>application/x-aerovault</mimetype>
  </mimetypes>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>AeroFTP main window showing dual-pane file browser</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Connection screen with saved servers</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>AeroTools with code editor, terminal and AI assistant</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/axpdev-lab/aeroftp</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/axpnet</url>

  <developer id="com.aeroftp">
    <name>Ale (axpdev)</name>
  </developer>

  <provides>
    <binary>aeroftp</binary>
  </provides>

  <languages>
    <lang percentage="100">en</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">it</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">de</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">es</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">fr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">pt</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ru</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ja</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ko</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">zh</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">bn</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">tr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">pl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">nl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sv</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">da</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">fi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">no</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">is</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">cs</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hu</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ro</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">uk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">el</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">th</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">vi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">id</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ms</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">tl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">km</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ka</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hy</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">bg</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">mk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">et</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">lt</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">lv</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">cy</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ca</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">gl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">eu</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sw</lang>
  </languages>

  <releases>
    <release version="3.5.3" date="2026-04-16">
      <description>
        <p>Continuous Sync, MCP Integration and CLI Expansion. CLI sync --watch adds native filesystem watcher with continuous bidirectional sync, anti-loop protection, incremental local scan, and NDJSON output. MCP Server dialog and VS Code extension for AI assistant integration. New CLI flags: --files-from, --immutable, --no-check-dest, --max-depth, --inplace, --fast-list, --compare-dest, --copy-dest. Critical fix for FTP and WebDAV listing path construction in recursive operations. Azure Blob directory markers. 11 new unit tests.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.5.2" date="2026-04-15">
      <description>
        <p>CLI determinism: 12 structured exit codes, idempotent mkdir -p, rm -f, put --no-clobber. Performance: configurable chunk/buffer sizes, S3 parallel multipart upload, Azure server-side copy, dynamic file-size timeout for slow connections. Security: STRIDE threat model, LLM integration guide, multi-agent audit with 6 findings fixed, unified error sanitization, path traversal prevention. UX: parent folder double-click, drag disabled during rename, grid font scaling, overwrite dialog timestamp tolerance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.5.1" date="2026-04-14">
      <description>
        <p>Critical transfer fix: replaced 30-second global timeout with connect + read timeout across all 22 cloud providers. MEGA Native streaming rewrite eliminates out-of-memory on large files. Security hardening with zeroization and constant-time comparison. Azure Blob trash management. Zoho versioning enabled. Protocol switch FTP/SFTP in edit mode. IntroHub dynamic tab labels. Grid virtualization for 10K+ files.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.5.0" date="2026-04-13">
      <description>
        <p>Profile Bridge hub: unified import/export for rclone, WinSCP, and FileZilla with contextual UI. FileZilla sitemanager.xml bridge with base64 password decoding. Nextcloud WebDAV auto-detection. Transfer engine fixes: size-based timeout for large files, skip-if-identical action mapping, retry queue callback preservation, AeroSync crash fix. UI polish: hover animation, drag/rename conflict, parent folder double-click, font scaling, Ukrainian/Russian i18n fix.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.9" date="2026-04-13">
      <description>
        <p>WinSCP import/export bridge with password decoding and vault upgrade. macOS menu bar Quit fix. WebDAV 405 fallback (community contribution). Security hardening: CLI credential redaction, import/export path validation, INI injection prevention. Delete confirmation for saved servers. Media filter tab. CLI banner redesign. Six dependency updates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.8" date="2026-04-10">
      <description>
        <p>Cross-profile transfer with floating panel for server-to-server file copy. CLI doctor workflows (sync-doctor, transfer-doctor) and agent-bootstrap. Zoho/GitLab/Swift rate limit retry. UI polish: modal consistency, select field padding, provider icon badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.7" date="2026-04-09">
      <description>
        <p>Import and export rclone configurations: import server profiles from rclone.conf with automatic password upgrade to encrypted vault, export to rclone.conf for CLI use. Supports 17 rclone backend types including FTP, SFTP, S3, WebDAV, Google Drive, Dropbox, OneDrive, and MEGA. New CLI subcommand: aeroftp import rclone. Fixed MEGA default mode to Native API.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.5" date="2026-04-08">
      <description>
        <p>AppImage cross-distro fix: stripped bundled libraries to resolve EGL_BAD_PARAMETER on Arch/Fedora/rolling distros (118 MB to 48 MB). Client-side window resize for undecorated windows on Linux Wayland and X11. Minimum height lowered to 600px for 768p screens. Monaco editor expanded to 80+ languages including Lua, Kotlin, Dart, Elixir, and Terraform. Corrected provider contact badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.4" date="2026-04-07">
      <description>
        <p>Immich photo management provider: native REST API integration with albums, upload/download, delete, search, share links, and SHA-256 checksums. PixelUnion EU-hosted preset (16 GB free). New Media Services category in Discover. Full CLI support. Transfer infrastructure: FTP session pool, transfer orchestrator, event bridge.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.3" date="2026-04-06">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync advanced controls: conflict strategies, delete orphans with versioning, rename detection, file filters, bandwidth schedules, transfer budgets, snapshot rollback. Archive security hardening. Provider trash management for Box, Zoho, MEGA, OpenDrive, Yandex, pCloud, KDrive. Plugin integrity verification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.2" date="2026-04-05">
      <description>
        <p>CLI Pro: FUSE mount (read-write, cross-platform), ncdu TUI disk explorer, serve FTP/SFTP, background daemon with job queue, zero-knowledge crypt overlay (AES-256-GCM), bisync with snapshot and conflict resolution, transfer controls (retries, max-transfer, dump). ASPnix hosting provider integration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.1" date="2026-04-05">
      <description>
        <p>Fix FTPS implicit TLS on port 990 (CerberusFTP). Fix Azure Blob health check. SourceForge links in About dialog.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.4.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <description>
        <p>Google Cloud Storage provider with HMAC interop. Fix S3 HTTP/2 protocol error. Translated Discover panel descriptions (46 languages).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.9" date="2026-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Fix TLS session reuse on data connections for CerberusFTP and strict servers by capping FTP TLS to version 1.2 (RFC 4217).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.8" date="2026-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Fix Windows TLS certificate validation for Let's Encrypt and system-trusted CAs. Clean up InfiniCloud connection form.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.7" date="2026-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Rebex FTP/SFTP demo servers in Discover tab for instant onboarding. InfiniCloud REST API v2 module for auto-discovery and quota (pending API key). Fixed broken signup/help URLs for 5 providers. Corrected Cryptomator capability (create + browse, not read-only). Azure Blob moved to Object Storage section. Redirect to My Servers after saving. Subtle shield badge for unverified TLS certificates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.6" date="2026-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>FTPS TLS session reuse: migrated from native-tls to rustls, enabling automatic TLS session resumption on data connections (RFC 4217). Fixes compatibility with CerberusFTP, vsftpd, FileZilla Server, and ProFTPD when session reuse is required. Color-coded server badges (FTPS green, SFTP teal, FTP amber) with TLS security indicators. Fixed saved server host:port duplication and TLS mode persistence.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.5" date="2026-04-03">
      <description>
        <p>CLI serve HTTP/WebDAV: expose any remote as local HTTP (read-only, range requests) or WebDAV (read-write with PROPFIND/PUT/DELETE/MKCOL/MOVE/COPY). Native MCP server for Claude Desktop/Cursor/VS Code integration. AI stream cancellation, Anthropic prompt caching (90% cost reduction). GitLab Tier 1: releases, merge requests, write mode, self-hosted TLS. Streaming folder transfers (10-30x faster first-byte). Provider range downloads for FTP/S3/WebDAV. 13 bug fixes including auto-restart and health check reliability.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.4" date="2026-04-03">
      <description>
        <p>Ollama local AI fix: models now appear in chat dropdown, status indicator shows green, tool calls work correctly. Update verification shows green SHA-256 badge instead of amber warning. Reliable app restart after update using PID-polling instead of fixed timeout. Auto-imported AI models now have tools enabled by default.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.3" date="2026-04-02">
      <description>
        <p>Provider health check dashboard: progressive wave scan with status indicators on Discover service cards. S3 Advanced Options with locked preset fields and edit warning. Provider logos in connect buttons. AWS theme-aware logo. Form card redesign: unified styling, card footer with links, 2-line disclaimer. Form tab context menu and origin memory. S3 folder delete fix for MinIO. Font customization and window state persistence. GitLab integration. 51 integrated services across 6 protocols. Documentation reorganized: Technical Reference and Setup Guides.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.0" date="2026-04-01">
      <description>
        <p>IntroHub redesign: new tabbed interface with My Servers grid, Discover Services catalog (49 providers), Command Palette (Ctrl+K), and dynamic form tabs. Custom animated checkboxes. SourceForge native SFTP integration. SFTP upload fix (host key mismatch). Auto-update trust UI with Sigstore verification badges. Linux restart reliability fix. 47-language info banners.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.6" date="2026-03-31">
      <description>
        <p>macOS static linking fix (liblzma). HIGH vulnerability resolved (russh 0.57 to 0.59). XSS SAST finding fixed. Felicloud direct access and badge. Aikido Security audit: Top 5% benchmark.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.5" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>Hotfix: Linux localhost bind regression. Plugin now binds to 127.0.0.1 explicitly.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.4" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>Session management, Blomp Swift provider, CLI batch engine with parallel transfers, agent memory system, speech-to-text transcription.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.3" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>Drime Cloud (21st provider), activity log improvements, credential masking, ScanningToast UX polish.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.2" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>Advanced Share Links with password, expiration, and permissions for 13 providers. MEGA S4 Object Storage (S3-compatible, 4 regions). CLI link command with --password/--expires/--permissions. Google Drive commenter role. MEGAcmd re-export fix, trash path sanitization, S4 capability gating. MEGA default tab set to Native API.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.0" date="2026-03-29">
      <description>
        <p>MEGA Native API: full client-side encryption without MEGAcmd. Dual-backend (Native API or MEGAcmd), RSA session auth, AES-128-CTR file encryption, trash management, share links. Windows console flash fix. Trash date formatting across all 11 providers.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.8" date="2026-03-29">
      <description>
        <p>Desktop security hardening: Sigstore client-side update verification, backend AI tool approval with native OS dialogs, vault passphrase moved to OS keyring, plugin registry fail-closed. Security documentation restructured.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.7" date="2026-03-28">
      <description>
        <p>Glob pattern matching for find across 8 providers, MEGA find exit code fix, Blomp hidden in production.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.6" date="2026-03-28">
      <description>
        <p>FeliCloud (20th provider): EU/GDPR Nextcloud cloud with OCS share links and trash management. Share Link Modal with copy confirmation and password display. Activity log coverage for 14 trash managers and 30+ provider operations. Fixed 4shared OAuth1 signature, Google Drive soft-delete, MEGA download and trash path, Dropbox restore. FileLu listing 2x faster via parallel API calls.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.5" date="2026-03-27">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent hardening: prompt caching, tool result caching, structured transfer plans, CLI/MCP parity, SQLite agent memory, local voice input via whisper.cpp. Independent security audit (19 findings, 17 resolved). CLI evolution: 30 subcommands, parallel transfers, resume, config.toml, aliases, MCP resources, FTP/FTPS certificate hardening. macOS entitlements fix for frozen UI on launch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.4" date="2026-03-27">
      <description>
        <p>Provider sprint: S3 enterprise features (storage class, SSE, object tagging, Glacier restore), Azure blob tier management and soft-delete recovery, FileLu v2 API migration (path-based), kDrive trash manager, Hetzner Storage Box preset, FTP hash/checksum commands, ProvidersDialog enterprise column. AeroCloud closure: VersionBrowser browse-all mode, path traversal hardening, dynamic checksum comparison. FileLu promoted to stable (12/23 protocols). 6 external audit findings resolved.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.3" date="2026-03-26">
      <description>
        <p>AeroCloud hardening: 6-phase sprint covering engine hardening, protocol fixes (OpenDrive, FileLu, 4shared), selective sync, file versioning (.aeroversions/), .aeroignore support, protocol maturity badges. 10 audit findings resolved.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.2" date="2026-03-25">
      <description>
        <p>Zoho WorkDrive full MCP parity: all 22 tools covered, native Zoho document creation with auto-conversion to Office formats, share link management UI, getUserInfo, enhanced OAuth scopes. New Swap Panels setting to place local panel on the left and remote on the right, matching classic FTP client layout.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.1" date="2026-03-24">
      <description>
        <p>GitHub integration hardening: 5-auditor security audit remediation, streaming downloads, rate limit retry, Settings 3-mode auth editor, AeroCloud dedicated tab with full configuration, official GitHub octicons, live Actions status indicator. All 3 GitHub auth modes (OAuth, PAT, App) verified with separate vault storage.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.0" date="2026-03-23">
      <description>
        <p>Co-Author address book for GitHub commits with persistent contact list and one-click toggle. Windows static CRT linking eliminates vcruntime140.dll dependency for clean installs and winget validation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.9" date="2026-03-22">
      <description>
        <p>GitHub batch operations: atomic multi-file commits via GraphQL (no more 1-commit-per-file), unpushed local commit detection with push-first workflow. CLI: about and dedupe commands, bandwidth scheduling, rename tracking in sync. WiX installer image fix for readable text on Windows MSI wizard. ProvidersDialog unified layout.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.8" date="2026-03-21">
      <description>
        <p>CLI Feature Parity: 5 new commands (head, tail, hashsum, touch, check), advanced filter system (include/exclude, size, age), sync safety (max-delete), profile UX overhaul (no URL placeholder needed). 4shared OAuth 1.0 and Azure container auto-detection from profiles. 12 providers tested live. Complete CLI documentation rewrite.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.7" date="2026-03-21">
      <description>
        <p>Filen Encrypted Notes (Beta): E2E encrypted notes with per-note AES-256-GCM keys, auto-save, version history, and tag management. Provider trash managers moved from context menu to dedicated toolbar buttons for 10 cloud providers. Connect loading spinner prevents double-click. GitHub file listings now show modification dates. Saved Servers buttons restyled with colored badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.6" date="2026-03-21">
      <description>
        <p>GitHub Actions monitor with live workflow status, re-run, and cancel. Universal file search filter for all 22 providers. GitHub App co-authoring fix for proper contributor attribution. PEM, PAT, and OAuth credentials stored in encrypted vault for instant multi-repo setup. 4-finding code audit remediation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.5" date="2026-03-20">
      <description>
        <p>Critical SFTP upload fix: replaced russh-sftp write backend with ssh2/SCP for reliable file delivery. Atomic download writes across all 22 providers. Complete GitHub integration: multi-repo, Pages browser, co-authoring with aeroftp[bot], PEM vault storage, CHANGELOG import in Release Browser.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.4" date="2026-03-19">
      <description>
        <p>GitHub Integration: Release Browser with create, download, and delete. PR creation button in branch workflow. Batch commit via GraphQL. Public/private repository badge. Critical fix: Monaco editor preview and save now works on all 23 protocols, not just FTP/SFTP. 8 CLI security audit findings resolved. Snap Store auto-publish re-enabled.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.3" date="2026-03-18">
      <description>
        <p>Comprehensive AeroAgent fixes: all 47 tools now correctly resolve relative paths, recursive directory upload with per-level mkdir, fixed Cohere and Perplexity streaming compatibility, server_exec credential lookup and TLS retry, empty message handling for reasoning models. Added Website and Documentation links in Help menu. AUR package switched from AppImage to .deb extraction to resolve EGL errors on Arch Linux.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.2" date="2026-03-18">
      <description>
        <p>Critical hotfix: folder upload with smart comparison (overwrite-if-newer) no longer navigates remote panel into last subdirectory. Settings changes apply immediately without requiring a file transfer to propagate. Session tabs locked during active transfers to prevent accidental server switching. Save button shows spinner feedback during vault write. Windows installer now auto-installs VC++ Runtime on clean systems, fixing STATUS_DLL_NOT_FOUND crash.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.1" date="2026-03-18">
      <description>
        <p>Critical fix for GitHub App (.pem) token generation panic. Comprehensive mtime preservation across all protocols (SFTP setstat, FTP MFMT, universal sync-level stat) to eliminate sync ping-pong. AeroCloud manual sync now works with all 23 protocols. GitHub protected branch bypass for users with ruleset permissions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2026-03-17">
      <description>
        <p>GitHub as 23rd protocol: browse repositories as filesystem, upload files that create commits, manage release assets. Three authentication modes including custom GitHub App identity with your own logo in commits. Branch awareness with automatic working branch for protected branches. Dual 10-auditor security review. CLI vault profiles for credential-isolated AI agent workflows.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.9" date="2026-03-17">
      <description>
        <p>CLI vault profiles: connect to any saved server with --profile flag, zero credentials exposed. Critical fix for FTP/TLS upload truncation and WebDAV HTTP 0-byte uploads. 5-auditor security hardening (83 findings, all resolved). WebDAV streaming upload eliminates memory issues on large files. OAuth providers accessible from CLI when authorized via GUI.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.8" date="2026-03-16">
      <description>
        <p>OpenDrive native REST API as 22nd protocol (5 GB free, session auth, trash management). Yandex Disk trash manager fully wired with context menu. Critical fix for Windows credential persistence — server profiles no longer disappear after saving. Import/export credential error handling improved. 9 new OpenDrive i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.7" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
        <p>Share links for FTP/SFTP/WebDAV servers via configurable Public URL Base mapping. Folder scan progress toast with real-time counters during recursive delete and download. Fullscreen overlay during app update installation. Security audit: URL scheme validation, debug-level logging, path resolution fix. 15 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.6" date="2026-03-14">
      <description>
        <p>Critical timezone fix: remote file timestamps (MLSD, SFTP, cloud APIs) now correctly converted from UTC to local timezone for display. Fixes overwrite-if-newer and sync comparisons producing incorrect results due to timezone offset. Frontend formatDate handles ISO 8601 with Z suffix, RFC 2822, and timezone offsets. 11 provider backends updated. CLI help banner added.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.5" date="2026-03-13">
      <description>
        <p>Dual-engine security audit (Claude Opus 4.6 + GPT-5.4): 117 findings across 8 areas, all P0-P2 remediated. DOMPurify sanitization on all dangerouslySetInnerHTML. Vault write crash safety with fsync error propagation. Keystore import all-or-nothing rollback. Shell denylist expansion. TOTP-before-cache enforcement. Yandex Object Storage S3 preset (BETA).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.4" date="2026-03-13">
      <description>
        <p>Server Health Check with real-time network diagnostics (DNS, TCP, TLS, HTTP probes) and health scoring. Download mtime preservation fixes sync and overwrite-if-newer accuracy. AeroSync gains Pull and Remote Backup presets for Remote-to-Local sync. AeroVault Pro modular architecture with recent vaults history and folder encryption. Server context menu. Provider Integration Guide. Snap Store auto-publish paused pending review.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.3" date="2026-03-11">
      <description>
        <p>AeroVault OS integration fix: MIME icons for Yaru/Adwaita/Papirus themes, Open-with handler, CVE-2026-31812 security patch</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.2" date="2026-03-10">
      <description>
        <p>CLI Expansion and AeroVault OS Integration: Production CLI with 14 commands, batch scripting engine (.aeroftp scripts with variables and error policies), glob pattern transfers, and tree command. Backend-agnostic AI core abstraction layer (EventSink, CredentialProvider, RemoteBackend traits). Cross-platform .aerovault file association with custom MIME type icon (shield+lock) for Linux, Windows, and macOS. Snap Store description compliance fix. 45-finding CLI security audit resolved.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.1" date="2026-03-08">
      <description>
        <p>Snap Store fix, MEGA clickable session badge, Jottacloud token persistence, auto-open Activity Log on sync completion, and security audit documentation updates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.0" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <p>Cloud Provider Audit and Security Hardening: 6 GPT-5.4 residual findings resolved (journal signing key moved process-side, provider password zeroization, Cryptomator SecretString, WebDAV insecure detection, shell denylist expanded to 35 patterns). AeroCloud rebranded from FTP-based to multi-protocol (20 protocols). AeroVault v2 extracted to standalone crate on crates.io.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.9" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <p>AeroVault Crate Extraction: AeroVault v2 encryption engine extracted to standalone aerovault crate on crates.io. Inline crypto code replaced with crate dependency, eliminating 2100 lines. Full backward compatibility with existing vaults verified. README updated with crates.io and docs.rs badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.8" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <p>Updater Hotfix: Corrected GitHub repository URL in updater whitelist. Added Privacy Policy document.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.7" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <p>Security Audit Grade A- and Server Duplication: Cross-audit with 45+ security findings resolved. Updater hardened with URL whitelist and path validation. CSP connect-src restricted to IPC-only. KDF upgraded to Argon2id 128 MiB for exports. Credential zeroization at all call sites. OAuth1 secrets auto-zeroized on drop. Extreme Mode circuit breaker. AeroAgent paste bug fixed. New server duplication feature for cloning saved servers with one click. License system removed — AeroFTP desktop is fully open source with no Pro restrictions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.6" date="2026-03-05">
      <description>
        <p>Cloud Provider Audit and Security Hardening: Comprehensive audit of all 13 cloud providers with all findings resolved. Google Drive no longer creates duplicates on upload. OneDrive resume upload now works correctly. MEGA delete operations unified to use recycle bin. Box rename supports cross-folder moves. Internxt HTTP calls now have exponential backoff retry. FileLu upload uses streaming to prevent OOM. Shell command injection via newlines blocked. CSP tightened by removing unsafe-eval.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.5" date="2026-03-05">
      <description>
        <p>pCloud Fix and UX Polish: Fixed pCloud connection, upload, and EU region detection. OAuth re-authentication now triggers automatically on invalid tokens. Status bar quota no longer shows stale data when switching servers. AeroVault password Tab key no longer gets trapped on visibility toggle.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.4" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
        <p>OAuth Setup and UI Consistency: OAuth credentials form now shows the exact Redirect URI with copy button. S3 saved server subtitles show provider names from registry. Settings server list displays favicons and custom icons. Cloud Providers tab uses official provider logos. Dark theme unified across 4 remaining modal dialogs (CryptomatorCreate, BoxTags, ChatHistory, FileLu).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.3" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
        <p>OAuth UX Polish: Pro nag banner hidden in production (dev-only). 4shared local folder field restored in active state. OAuth account summary with masked credentials shown below Connect button.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.2" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
        <p>pCloud Production Activation: pCloud OAuth2 with automatic US/EU region detection is now available to all users. Previously gated behind dev-only flag.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.1" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
        <p>Auto-Update Reliability and WinGet CI: Update toast no longer appears when platform binary is not yet uploaded by CI. Post-install restart on Linux fixed — executable path captured before dpkg/rpm replaces the binary. Asset retry reduced from 1 hour to 30 minutes. WinGet Releaser added to CI for automatic Windows Package Manager updates. 3 High CVEs fixed via aws-lc-sys update. suppaftp pinned at 8.0.1 for Windows compatibility.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.0" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
        <p>Koofr Native API, Production CLI and AeroAgent Server Exec: Koofr joins as the 20th protocol with native REST API and OAuth2 PKCE (10 GB free, EU-based). Production CLI binary (aeroftp-cli) with 13 commands across all 20 protocols, URL-based connections, progress bars, and --json output. AeroAgent gains server_list_saved and server_exec tools to operate on any saved server — credentials resolved securely from vault, never exposed to AI. Ed25519 license infrastructure (dev-only). 3-auditor security review with all findings resolved. Dark theme modal alignment fix. 36 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.5" date="2026-03-02">
      <description>
        <p>AeroCloud Multi-Protocol Fix and CLI JSON Output: Critical fixes for AeroCloud background sync with SFTP and WebDAV protocols. Server field parsing now correctly separates hostname from embedded port, fixing DNS resolution failures and malformed WebDAV URLs. WebDAV navigation enforces root boundary. CLI gains --json flag for machine-readable output on all 5 commands.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.4" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
        <p>Complete Provider Integration: Full feature sets for Box, Google Drive, OneDrive, and Zoho WorkDrive. Box gains trash, move, comments, collaborations, watermark, folder locks, tags. Google Drive adds starring with visible badge and comments dialog. OneDrive adds move-to-trash. Zoho WorkDrive adds file versioning. New Providers and Integrations dialog with feature matrix for all 31 providers. PRO badge system, 60+ new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.3" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
        <p>Stabilized home intro panels that were resizing in certain circumstances.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.2" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
        <p>FileLu Provider Fixes and Provider UX: Corrects the FileLu free tier from 20 GB to the accurate 1 GB across all documentation and provider descriptions. Fixes a quota display bug where the StatusBar showed raw byte values instead of gigabytes. Fixes the connection name placeholder showing "My Filen Cloud" instead of "My FileLu Cloud". Cloud providers are now ordered by free storage tier, and every provider card description includes its free quota.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.1" date="2026-02-26">
      <description>
        <p>S3 Provider Preset UX and Cloudflare R2 Account ID: Overhauled S3 connection forms so all preset fields (endpoint, region) are visible, pre-filled, and follow the disabled-plus-Edit pattern. Cloudflare R2 now has a dedicated Account ID input that auto-computes the endpoint with an Edit escape hatch for future-proofing. Fixed endpoint resolution for endpointTemplate providers and backward-compatible editing of saved servers.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.0" date="2026-02-26">
      <description>
        <p>FileLu Native API — 19th Protocol: Added FileLu cloud storage as the 19th supported protocol via its native REST API. Includes privacy-focused features: per-file and per-folder password protection, public/private visibility toggle, server-side file cloning, trash management with restore and permanent delete, and remote URL upload. Also adds FileLu FTP, FTPS, WebDAV, and S3 presets for users who prefer standard protocols.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.10" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>CI Recovery and Release Realignment: Fixed a TypeScript parsing issue in ProtocolSelector that interrupted release builds, and re-aligned the release pipeline to publish downloadable artifacts correctly across supported platforms.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.9" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Seafile Preset and Transfer Circuit Breaker: Added a pre-configured Seafile WebDAV preset with dedicated logo and full i18n coverage. Introduced a batch transfer circuit breaker with error classification, exponential backoff, reconnect handling, and retry-all-failed support for improved reliability during unstable connections.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.8" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Selective Server Export: Export individual servers instead of all-or-nothing. The Export dialog now shows a checklist with Select All / Deselect All, color badges, protocol labels, and a live counter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.7" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Update Restart, UX Polish and AeroCloud Multi-Protocol: Fixed long-standing restart failure on .deb, .rpm, and AppImage using setsid() detached relaunch. AeroCloud background sync now supports all 18 protocols via cloud provider factory. Dark theme modal consistency fix. Dynamic FTP TLS badge. Unified S3/WebDAV provider selector with info cards. Connection save race condition fix. SFTP symlink directory detection for NAS devices. 14 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.5" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Dual-Engine Security Audit Remediation: Comprehensive security hardening based on dual-engine audit (8 Claude Opus 4.6 agents + GPT-5.3-Codex). 94 findings fixed across all severity levels — 7 Critical, 27 High, 54 Medium, 6 Low. Key fixes: constant-time HMAC comparison in AeroVault (subtle crate), bounded manifest reads (64MB cap), archive extraction path traversal guard for TAR/7z/RAR, 2FA enforcement in vault unlock, shell meta-character blocking, atomic writes for vault mutations and file saves, download size caps (500MB) across 13 providers, PTY session isolation, image resize bounds, SVG sanitization, credential redaction on profile import, unlock throttling with exponential backoff. Post-remediation grade: A-. 178 new i18n keys translated across all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.4" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Custom Server Icons and Favicon Detection: Custom icon picker for servers without dedicated provider logos — choose any image file, resized to 128x128 PNG. Automatic favicon detection for FTP/FTPS/SFTP servers using SIZE pre-check to avoid data channel corruption. Icon priority: custom icon, auto-detected favicon, provider logo, initial letter. Vault storage race condition fix ensuring icons persist across reconnections. Monaco source map dev warning silenced.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.3" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>AeroCloud Tab Switch and Menu Restoration: Critical fix for AeroCloud tab switching — switching from provider tabs (kDrive, Drime, etc.) back to AeroCloud now correctly disconnects the active provider before reconnecting. Session protocol routing expanded from hardcoded list to isNonFtpProvider() covering all 17 non-FTP protocols. Restored missing "Check for Updates" menu item in Help menu lost during VS Code-style titlebar migration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.2" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>Amazon S3 Provider and Protocol Enablement: Dedicated Amazon S3 provider with 28 AWS region presets, official AWS logo, and simplified connection UI (no manual endpoint or path-style configuration). S3 bucket name trimming fix for IDNA validation errors. Azure Blob and Drime Cloud protocols re-enabled for production after successful testing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.1" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>VS Code-Style Titlebar and UX Polish: Unified VS Code-style titlebar with 4 custom dropdown menus (File, Edit, View, Help), theme-aware accent color hover, and migrated toolbar buttons. Native GTK menu bar eliminated. Cut/Copy/Paste in Edit menu with selection-aware disabled states. Consistent animate-scale-in animation on all 42 modal dialogs. Click-outside-to-close on AeroVault and Master Password dialogs. Default backgrounds updated (Waves for app, Isometric for lock screen). 147 provider security audit findings remediated across 8 cloud providers. ErrorBoundary and DebugPanel crash fixes. Settings button in titlebar. Simplified View menu labels in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.0" date="2026-02-22">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Ecosystem, Cloud Expansion and Provider Tier 3: Two new cloud storage protocols (Internxt Drive with E2E encryption, Infomaniak kDrive) bringing the total to 18. Four new AI providers (AI21 Labs, Cerebras, SambaNova, Fireworks AI) bringing the total to 19. Command Palette (Ctrl+Shift+P) with 25 commands across 5 categories. Plugin ecosystem with GitHub-based registry, SHA-256 integrity verification, Plugin Browser UI with install/update/remove, and event-driven plugin hooks. Context menu AI actions for instant file analysis. AI Status Widget in StatusBar with real-time state indicator. Drag and drop files to AeroAgent chat for analysis. AUR package (aeroftp-bin) for Arch Linux. 19 new i18n keys translated in all 47 languages. 8 dependency updates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.2" date="2026-02-21">
      <description>
        <p>AeroImage — Built-in Image Editor: Lightweight image editor integrated into Universal Preview modal. Crop with Photoshop-style overlay and aspect ratio presets, resize with aspect lock, rotate and flip, brightness/contrast/hue adjustments with live CSS filter preview, blur/sharpen/grayscale/invert effects. Save As dialog with 6 output formats (PNG, JPEG, WebP, BMP, TIFF, GIF), JPEG quality slider, and replace-original option. Rust process_image pipeline for pixel-perfect output. Fix for auto-update installation on systems with localized Downloads folder names. 49 new i18n keys translated in all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.1" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>Clippy Clean, Zoho Tab Icon and CI Fixes: Resolved 254 Clippy warnings across 42 Rust source files. MSRV updated from 1.77.2 to 1.80.0. Zoho WorkDrive session tab now displays official provider logo instead of generic WiFi icon. CI quality gates hardened with i18n validation scripts committed to repo. 3 missing protocol translation keys added to all 46 non-English locales. Dependabot configured with ignore rules for intentionally pinned dependencies.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.0" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>AeroFile Pro: Modularization, Tabs, Tags, Keyboard Navigation, Accessibility, macOS FinderSync, and event-driven volume detection. App.tsx modularized by extracting 730 lines into LocalFilePanel. Tabbed directory browsing (12 max, drag-to-reorder, persistence). Finder-style file tagging with SQLite (7 color labels, context menu, sidebar filtering). Arrow key navigation for file selection (Up/Down/Shift+Arrow for range). ARIA accessibility baseline (role=grid, aria-selected, role=toolbar, role=status). macOS FinderSync .appex extension for native Finder sync badges (6 states, Unix socket bridge, universal binary). Event-driven mount watcher (poll + inotify) replaces 5s polling. Network volume eject with fusermount fallback for SSHFS/NFS/CIFS. Mount point octal escaping fix for multi-byte UTF-8 paths. 23 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.4.0" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Provider Integration Audit and Zoho WorkDrive: 16th protocol with full OAuth2 and 8 regional endpoints. Comprehensive 12-auditor provider integration audit (4 phases, grade A-). Streaming upload refactor across 5 providers eliminates OOM on large files. All provider credentials wrapped in SecretString for memory zeroization. XML parsing migrated from regex to quick-xml 0.39. StorageProvider trait expanded to 18 methods with trash management, versioning, search, and share links. Cross-audit gap analysis: 18 findings fixed — HTTP retry with exponential backoff, provider error sanitization (95 occurrences), SFTP symlink-safe rmdir, AeroVault chunk AAD hardening, vault key zeroize on drop, cross-platform trash API, Windows volume enumeration via WinAPI. Resource management: all 17 issues resolved including local file scan 1M cap, Google Drive LRU cache, transfer pool validation. AeroSync Enterprise Intelligence: dry-run export (JSON/CSV), safety score pre-sync indicator, explainable sync decisions. SFTP TOFU visual dialog (SEC-P1-06): PuTTY-style host key verification with SHA-256 fingerprint display, MITM warning on key change, silent acceptance removed. Branded Polkit update dialog with AeroFTP icon and localized messages (10 languages). Auto-update restart fix for deb/rpm via detached shell relaunch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.0" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Chat History SQLite Redesign: Complete rewrite of chat history persistence from JSON flat-file to SQLite WAL + FTS5 full-text search. 18 Tauri commands for CRUD, search, export/import, branches, stats, cleanup, and clear-all. Chat History Manager UI with retention policies (7/30/90/180/365 days or unlimited), full-text search with highlighted snippets, session browser, and statistics dashboard. In-memory fallback for graceful degradation. 55+ security audit findings resolved from 5 independent auditors. 24 new i18n keys translated across all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.4" date="2026-02-18">
      <description>
        <p>Provider Marketplace, 2FA Vault, Remote Vault, CLI and Security Hardening: Searchable Provider Marketplace modal with 15 AI providers across 6 categories. 5 new providers (Mistral, Groq, Perplexity, Cohere, Together AI). TOTP two-factor authentication for vault master password with rate limiting. Remote Vault support for opening .aerovault files on connected servers. CLI foundation (aeroftp-cli binary with connect/ls/get/put/sync). CSP violation reporter. 13 security findings fixed from 5-auditor review.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.3" date="2026-02-17">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Welcome Screen and Shell Execute: Professional welcome screen with Lucide icons, 3x3 capability grid, API key setup detection, and clickable quick prompts. New shell_execute backend tool captures real stdout/stderr/exit code (replaces terminal_execute). i18n structural audit fixes 1188 leaked keys across 45 locales. Error message translation paths corrected. 29 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.2" date="2026-02-16">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent File Management Pro: 9 new tools (batch move, copy, trash, rename, disk usage, find duplicates, archive compress/decompress). Extreme Mode for fully autonomous 50-step AI execution (Cyber theme only). Relative path resolution fix for all 14 local tools. Connection context awareness distinguishes AeroCloud, server, and AeroFile modes. AeroSync modal now themed across all 4 themes via CSS custom properties. 13 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.1" date="2026-02-16">
      <description>
        <p>Splash screen menu bar flash fix (race condition in APP_READY_DONE timing). New Security Toolkit lock-and-key icon. New Cyber hacker theme icon. AeroCloud default sync interval set to 24h with inotify active.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.0" date="2026-02-15">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 3A+ — Complete Frontend Integration and UX Maturity: Tab-based UX (Quick Sync + Advanced), 5 Speed Mode presets, Sync Scheduler, Filesystem Watcher, Multi-Path Editor, Sync Templates, Rollback Snapshots, parallel streams (1-8). Professional splash screen with 21-step simulated loading sequence. Advanced tab accordion for compact navigation. Password Forge extended to 24-word passphrases with BIP-39 disclaimer. Cyber shield icon. WebKitGTK scrollbar z-index fix. 31 security findings fixed across 6 independent auditors. Grade: A-. 47 languages at 100%.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.2" date="2026-02-15">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 3A — Professional Sync Engine: 3 built-in sync profiles (Mirror, Two-way, Backup) with custom save/load. Conflict Resolution Center with per-file and batch strategies. Bandwidth control UI for upload/download speed limits. Journal auto-cleanup (30-day TTL). Backend progress throttle (150ms/2% delta) and parallel local+remote scan via tokio::join!. Plugin SHA-256 integrity verification. 39 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.1" date="2026-02-14">
      <description>
        <p>UX Polish, Icon Themes and Sync Reliability: 3-style icon theme system (Outline, Filled, Minimal) with per-theme defaults and auto-sync. Unified TransferProgressBar (7 bars into 1 reusable component with SpeedGraph). Aero Family branding complete. Fixed sync navigation false folder creation, AeroCloud CWD corruption on shared FTP connection, and session path restoration. Transfer toast theme/flicker fixes and splash screen removed for instant startup.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.0" date="2026-02-14">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 2 — Operational Reliability: Transfer journal with checkpoint/resume for interrupted syncs, SHA-256 streaming checksum during file scan, structured error taxonomy (10 categories with retryability hints), post-transfer verification (4 policies: none/size/size+time/full), configurable retry with exponential backoff. Session tab context menu, insecure certificate confirmation modal, Filen 2FA compatibility fix, and 23 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.11" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Complete i18n for Connection Intelligence: All 14 new connection logging and security badge keys translated across 45 languages with native quality. 360 placeholder corrections applied automatically.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.10" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Connection Intelligence, Security Badges and Windows Build Fix: DNS resolution with resolved IP in Activity Log, protocol step logging (TLS/SSH/HTTPS establishment, authentication, directory listing), secure connection badge (ShieldCheck with protocol abbreviation), 3-tier security model (insecure/warning/secure) in StatusBar, and suppaftp pinned to 8.0.1 to fix Windows build regression.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.9" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Smart Auto-Update with Platform-Native Installation: One-click Install and Restart for .deb, .rpm, .msi and .exe packages via platform-native tools (pkexec/msiexec). Smart asset availability detection retries hourly when CI artifacts are still building. Update toast UX redesigned with clear state progression. StatusBar badge re-triggers dismissed toast. 2 new i18n keys (openInstaller, skipForNow) translated in all 47 languages. Runtime version detection replaces compile-time macro.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.8" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Security Hardening, i18n Completion, Media Startup: Plugin shell injection eliminated (direct argv execution), TOFU host-key error branch hardened (fail-closed), localStorage OAuth fallback removed (vault-only credentials), terminal destructive command denylist, AeroCloud sync counters fixed with per-file activity details, security regression suite (5 automated checks with CI gate), settings migrated to vault-first storage, full locale key completion including Armenian, and Linux media first-play stabilized via buffered autoplay queue.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.7" date="2026-02-12">
      <description>
        <p>Translation Quality Audit: Comprehensive quality pass across all 47 languages. Eliminated 605 silent intruder keys (English values without markers), restored Armenian Unicode script from 63 Latin romanizations, applied 16 native Chinese corrections, standardized 173 placeholder formats, and translated 5 connection keys missing in 45 languages. Over 6,350 translations verified or corrected.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.6" date="2026-02-11">
      <description>
        <p>Theme System, Security Toolkit, Complete i18n: Four built-in themes (Light, Dark, Tokyo Night, Cyber) with CSS custom properties. Security Toolkit with Hash Forge (5 algorithms), CryptoLab (AES-256-GCM/ChaCha20 text encryption), and Password Forge (CSPRNG passwords + BIP39 passphrases). Terminal and Monaco editor auto-sync with app theme. 360 new i18n keys across 47 languages — zero untranslated strings. Monaco dev mode fix. About dialog updated.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.5" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>System Startup, Tray Icon, Windows Explorer Badge and Provider Cleanup: Autostart on system boot with toggle in Settings (cross-platform: LaunchAgent, .desktop, Registry). Standard white monochrome tray icon. Windows Explorer native sync badges via Cloud Filter API and Named Pipe IPC server. OwnCloud provider removed after Kiteworks acquisition. Protocol Selector UX fixes. Security audit: 7 findings fixed (bounded reader, reject remote pipe clients, idle timeout, UNC path blocking, RwLock poison recovery).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.4" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>Mission Green Badge, Folder Transfer UX and Transfer Reliability: Native overlay badges in Nautilus/Nemo file managers showing AeroCloud sync status (green checkmark for synced, blue arrows for syncing, red X for errors). Tray icon with overlay icons inside colored dots. Folder transfer cancel support, file-count progress display, path-aware logging. Transfer event system rewritten for zero event loss.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.3" date="2026-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>Production Rendering Fix: Critical fix for CSP nonce injection that silently broke all dynamic styles, Web Workers, WebGL, and IPC in production builds. Switched Monaco Editor to AMD loading for full WebKitGTK compatibility. Added DMABUF renderer workaround for Linux canvas artifacts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.2" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>AeroFile Pro, Security Hardening and AI Provider Audit: Professional local file manager with Quick Look (Space), Trash Browser, Enhanced Properties (3-tab with permissions and 4-algorithm checksums), Disk Usage Treemap, and Duplicate Finder. Massive security audit resolving 70 findings across AeroAgent AI system (22 fixes, A-) and AeroFile file manager (48 fixes, A-) — including path traversal prevention, resource exhaustion limits, memory leak fixes, iframe sandbox hardening, and prompt injection defense.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.1" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>Vault Unlock Fix and Provider Expansion: Fixed saved servers list appearing empty after master password entry. Added 3 Asian AI providers (Kimi, Qwen, DeepSeek) with official SVG logos. Added Custom provider preset for any OpenAI-compatible endpoint.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Pro: Professional AI assistant with 5-phase enhancement. Streaming markdown, code block actions, prompt templates, cost budget tracking, chat search. Anthropic prompt caching, OpenAI structured outputs, Ollama model templates and GPU monitoring. Gemini code execution and context caching. Context intelligence with project detection, smart context injection, and token budget optimization. DAG-based parallel tool execution, diff preview, intelligent retry, and composite macros.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Super Powers, Unified Keystore &amp; AeroPlayer Engine — 17 new features spanning autonomous AI agent capabilities, RAG intelligence, extensibility, encrypted vault directories, enterprise-grade credential security, and a fully rewritten media player with WebGL GPU shaders.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AeroPlayer: 14 visualizer modes (8 Canvas 2D + 6 WebGL GPU shaders), 10-band graphic EQ, beat detection, Cyber Mode</li>
          <li>WebGL shaders: Wave Glitch, VHS, Mandelbrot, Raymarch Tunnel, Metaball, Particles (ported from CyberPulse)</li>
          <li>AeroAgent: Multi-step autonomous tool calls, RAG workspace indexing, custom plugin system</li>
          <li>Ollama auto-detection, conversation export, system prompt editor, Monaco-Agent live sync</li>
          <li>Unified encrypted keystore with migration wizard and backup/restore</li>
          <li>AeroVault v2: Directory support with hierarchical navigation and recursive delete</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.9" date="2026-02-06">
      <description>
        <p>Dynamic Version Info, Credential Fix and Dependency Updates</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed critical credential save race condition for OAuth cloud providers</li>
          <li>Added vault write serialization (VAULT_WRITE_LOCK Mutex) to prevent concurrent write races</li>
          <li>Dynamic version info in About dialog (Rust, React, TypeScript, Tailwind detected at build time)</li>
          <li>Updated dependencies: Tauri 2.10.2, zip 7.4.0</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.8" date="2026-02-05">
      <description>
        <p>Security Hardening, Vision AI and Agent Intelligence</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Full security audit remediation: XSS prevention, CSP hardening, ZIP Slip fix, AI tool restrictions</li>
          <li>Vision/multimodal AI: attach images for analysis with GPT-4o, Claude, Gemini, Ollama</li>
          <li>Agent panel refresh: file panels auto-update after AI tool mutations</li>
          <li>Console.log gating behind debug-only logger utility</li>
          <li>Duplicate consolidation: formatBytes, getMimeType, UpdateInfo unified</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.0" date="2026-02-04">
      <description>
        <p>Smart Sync, AeroVault v2 Military-Grade Encryption</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Smart Sync with 3 intelligent conflict modes</li>
          <li>AeroVault v2: AES-256-GCM-SIV, Argon2id 128 MiB, HMAC-SHA512, optional ChaCha20 cascade</li>
          <li>Batch Rename with 4 modes and live preview</li>
          <li>Inline Rename with F2 or click</li>
          <li>Universal Credential Vault with optional master password</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="2026-02-01">
      <description>
        <p>Encryption Block, AeroFile Mode, AeroAgent Expansion</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AeroVault encrypted containers (.aerovault format)</li>
          <li>Archive browser for ZIP, 7z, TAR, RAR with selective extraction</li>
          <li>Cryptomator format 8 vault support</li>
          <li>AeroFile local-only file manager mode</li>
          <li>AeroAgent expanded to 24 tools with local file operations and batch transfers</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2026-01-31">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Pro: Native AI Function Calling and Streaming</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Native function calling for OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini</li>
          <li>Streaming responses with real-time rendering for all 7 providers</li>
          <li>14 provider-agnostic tools via StorageProvider trait</li>
          <li>Chat history persistence with cost tracking per message</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.5.0" date="2026-01-29">
      <description>
        <p>Cloud Expansion: Box, pCloud, Azure Blob, Filen</p>
        <ul>
          <li>4 new cloud providers: Box, pCloud, Azure Blob Storage, Filen</li>
          <li>13 protocols total with 30 presets</li>
          <li>Native clipboard with cross-panel drag and drop</li>
          <li>Integrated terminal with SSH remote shell</li>
          <li>In-app auto-updater with download progress</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.8" date="2026-01-25">
      <description>
        <p>Global Multilingual Edition (51 Languages)</p>
        <ul>
          <li>51 languages including RTL support (Arabic, Hebrew, Persian, Urdu)</li>
          <li>Smart Overwrite Dialog with file comparison</li>
          <li>Properties Dialog with checksum calculation (MD5/SHA-256)</li>
          <li>MEGA.nz integration with end-to-end encryption</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-01-20">
      <description>
        <p>First stable release with FTP, FTPS, SFTP, WebDAV, S3, Google Drive, Dropbox, OneDrive support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>FileTransfer</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>ftp</keyword>
    <keyword>sftp</keyword>
    <keyword>ftps</keyword>
    <keyword>webdav</keyword>
    <keyword>s3</keyword>
    <keyword>file transfer</keyword>
    <keyword>cloud storage</keyword>
    <keyword>encryption</keyword>
    <keyword>vault</keyword>
    <keyword>sync</keyword>
    <keyword>ai</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
</component>
